# Jeeva R



jeevasmart82@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/jeevasmart82



7200712356



https://jeevasmart.github.io

# **Summary**

IT Support Specialist with over 3+ years of IT Support Technician experience as a Freelancer and I am currently employed as a full-time employee in a reputed company.

Having basic knowledge of various AWS Cloud Services like EC2, S3, IAM.

I am currently responsible for providing all IT support such as troubleshooting, Remote Servers backup, Volume Licensing of software, maintaining G-Suite admin Activities, Endpoint Security, and Firewall. My previous position made me skilled in providing end-user help desk support and I can remain calm in difficult situations.

Having knowledge of Linux Servers (EC2), Hyper-V, Microsoft 365, G-Suite, Endpoint Security, and Firewall.

Tools: MobaXterm, Putty, WinSCP, FileZilla, VMware Horizon Client, S3 Browser.

# **Experience**

## **VECTRA Information Technology Support Assistant**

Vectra Automation, Inc.

Apr 2022 - Present (7 months +)

- 1. Coordinate with client IT support for Auto2D deployment and maintenance.
- 2. Installation and Volume Licensing of Big software like Solidworks, Catia v5, Inventor, Siemens NX.
- 3. Managing AWS Services like EC2,S3, IAM, and EBS Volume.
- 4. AWS server maintenance. Manage AWS HUB (ec2 instance) file system.
- 5. Manage and maintain G-Suite admin Activities.
- 6. Basic Office365 experience, such as checking user access provisioning, performing mail trace, etc.
- 7. Monitor and support client PC accessibility (VPN or Anydesk) and ensure that they are always online.
- 8. knowledge of WinSCP and Configuration of a custom FTP server for data upload and download.
- 9. Coordinate with vendors to resolve vendor-specific issues.
- 10. Performing and Monitoring Remote Servers backup (acronis true image backup).
- 11. Endpoint Security, Firewall & Security devices management(Symantec and Mcafee).
- 12. Managing company's Software licenses.
- 13. Working knowledge of Windows Registry and ways to add/remove registry.
- 14. Having knowledge in active directory, DNS, and DHCP.

# IT Hardware and Network Engineer

#### Self Employed

Dec 2017 - Present (4 years 11 months +)

- 1. Installation of the operating system (OS) and Driver updates.
- 2. Troubleshooting hardware and software issues.
- 3. Unlocking and Flashing of all mobile phones.
- 4. Hands-on experience with Windows/Linux/Mac OS environments.
- 5. ISP Routers and Switches Configuration.
- 6. Installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of LAN.
- 7. Installing anti-virus software and removing viruses.
- 8. Network Administration: Static IP and DHCP Configuration.
- 9. Windows OS, Installation, Formatting, Partitioning, Configuration, and Troubleshooting.

- 10. Maintenance of CCTV cameras, unmanaged switches, and routers provided by the ISP.
- 11. Setting up and sharing network printers.
- 12. Troubleshooting and resolving client system issues.

### **Education**

Kings Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer science Engineering Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

Arignar Anna Government Higher Secondary School

Higher Secondary School Certificate, Computer Science Jun 2015 - May 2017

Sri Saraswathi Vidhya Mandir Matriculation School Secondary School Leaving Certificate

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

Jun 2014 - May 2015

- Trundamentals & Computer Networking Udemy
- Computer Skills And Fundamentals Udemy UC-4499db11-8f3e-4ec7-9c34-d55f293fab54
- G Linux Tutorial Great Learning
- Google Workspace (G Suite) Udemy
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (SAA-C02) LinkedIn
- in Google Workspace Administration LinkedIn

#### **Skills**

Vendor Management • IT Management • Endpoint Security • Software Licensing • Windows 10 • Microsoft Office • Backup & Recovery Systems • Amazon S3 • Firewall Management • Windows Server